roomsketcher.com 2014-06-26

# RoomSketcher » privacy

## Privacy policy for RoomSketcher

Revised as per May 8 2013

Welcome to the RoomSketcher web site, a web site operated by RoomSketcher.no AS (“us,” “we,” or “RoomSketcher”). This privacy policy (the ‘Privacy Policy’) explains you of our policies with respect to information collected from any services and content, including the web site, provided by RoomSketcher (the “RoomSketcher Services”).

Your use of the RoomSketcher Services constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and your consent to the practices it describe.

We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or delete whole or portions of this Privacy Policy at any time without further notice. If we do this, we will post the changes to this Privacy Policy on RoomSketcher’s web site and the date of last revision will be indicated at the top of the Privacy Policy. It is your responsibility to regularly check the web site to determine if there have been changes to these Terms of Use and to review such changes.

The complete terms and conditions for your use of the RoomSketcher Services (the “Terms of Use”) are posted on RoomSketcher’s web site.

### AUTOMATIC COLLECTION OF NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION

When you visit and use the RoomSketcher Services, like when you visit most other websites, certain non-personal information about your visit is automatically logged, which may include information about the type of browser you use, the server name and IP address through which you access the internet, the date and time you access the RoomSketcher Services, the pages you access while at the RoomSketcher Services, and the internet address of the website, if any, from which you linked directly to the RoomSketcher Services. This information is not personally identifiable.

### PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

“Personally Identifiable Information” is any information that concerns you individually and would permit someone to contact you, for example, your name, address, telephone/fax number, email address, Social Security number or similar or any information you submitted to RoomSketcher that identifies you individually.

We will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it. Therefore, if you do not want us to obtain any personally identifiable information about you, do not submit it.

You can visit and browse RoomSketcher Services without revealing personally identifiable information about yourself. You may also choose to disclose personally identifiable information about yourself, which may be maintained as described below. We may collect personally identifiable information about you from the RoomSketcher Services by methods such as the following:

#### REGISTRATION FORMS

If you are offered the opportunity to enter a promotion, to become a registered user of the the RoomSketcher Services, or to opt-in to receive information about the RoomSketcher Services through another site, you must apply by filling out the registration form on RoomSketcher’s web site. This form requires certain personally identifiable information that may include, without limitation, your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, areas of interest, and/or a unique individual password.

#### TRANSACTIONS AND ACTIVITY

If you become a registered user or if you conduct transactions through the RoomSketcher Services, information about the transactions you engage in while on the website and your other activity on the RoomSketcher Services may be collected. This information may include, without limitation, areas of the website that you visit, content that you view, download or submit.

#### EMAIL AND OTHER VOLUNTARY COMMUNICATIONS

You may also choose to communicate with us through email, via our website, by telephone, in writing, or though other means. We collect the information in these communications, and such information may be personally identifiable.

### INFORMATION USE

RoomSketcher may use Personally Identifiable Information collected through its website primarily for such purposes as:

  * helping to establish and verify the identity of registered users
  * opening, maintaining, administering and servicing registered users’ accounts or memberships
  * processing, servicing or enforcing transactions and sending related communications
  * providing services and support to [registered] users
  * improving the website, including tailoring it to users’ preferences
  * providing users with product or service updates, promotional offers and other information about RoomSketcher and its affiliates
  * responding to your questions inquiries, comments and instructions
  * maintaining the security and integrity of its systems

RoomSketcher uses non-personal information collected automatically primarily to help it administer and improve the RoomSketcher Services. RoomSketcher may also use aggregated non-personal information to provide information about the RoomSketcher Services to advertisers, potential business partners and other unaffiliated entities.

RoomSketcher use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit and use the RoomSketcher Services. These companies may use non-personal information about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here.

### DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION

RoomSketcher does not provide personally identifiable information to unaffiliated third parties for their use in marketing directly to you. We may use unaffiliated companies to help it maintain and operate its website or for other reasons related to the operation of its business, and those companies may receive your personally identifiable information for that purpose. We may also disclose personally identifiable information about you in connection with legal requirements, such as in response to an authorized subpoena, governmental request or investigation, or as otherwise permitted by law. Finally, as RoomSketcher’s business develops, RoomSketcher may sell or buy corporate assets, and in such transactions customer information may be one of the transferred business assets. If RoomSketcher, its internet businesses, or substantially all of its assets, is acquired, customer information may be one of the assets transferred.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

By agreeing on using or accessing the RoomSketcher Services, a person must be of legal age in accordance with the laws of the country where the person has its registered address or from which the person use, access or downloads the RoomSketcher Services. If a person is not of legal age in accordance with the preceding, such person must have the consent of its parents to use or access the RoomSketcher Services. Information collected from a child will only be used by RoomSketcher in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Additionally, a persons parent or legal guardian may request that information about a person under the legal age shall be corrected or deleted from our files by contacting us at Customer Service +47 40 00 04 84. In such case, we reserve the right to terminate access of the person under legal age as a registered user of the RoomSketcher Services, if such termination is deemed necessary by us in order for us to operate the RoomSketcher Services in accordance with the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy.

### “COOKIES” AND ADVERTISERS

RoomSketcher’s servers, or the servers of companies that are used to operate the RoomSketcher Services, may place a “cookie” on your computer in order to allow you to use the RoomSketcher Services and to personalize your experience.

A “cookie” is a small piece of data that can be sent by a web server to your computer, which then may be stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies allow RoomSketcher to recognize your computer while you are on its website and help customize your online experience and make it more convenient for you. Cookies are also useful in allowing more efficient log-in for users, tracking transaction histories and preserving information between sessions. The information collected from cookies may also be used to improve the functionality of the website.

The advertisers and/or other content providers that may appear on this website may also use cookies that are not sent by the RoomSketcher Services. Such ads or content may contain cookies that help track and target the interests of users of this website in order to present “personalized” advertisements or other messages that the user might find interesting. We are not responsible for any such cookies.

Most web browser applications (such as Microsoft Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator) have features that can notify you when you receive a cookie or prevent cookies from being sent. If you disable cookies, however, you may not be able to use certain personalized functions of the RoomSketcher Services.

### EXTERNAL LINKS

The RoomSketcher Services may contain links to other websites, including those of advertisers or third party content providers who offer downloads on RoomSketcher Services. Please be aware that RoomSketcher is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. Websites that are accessible by hyperlinks from the RoomSketcher Services may use cookies. We encourage you to read the privacy statements provided by other websites before you provide personally identifiable information to them.

### SECURITY

RoomSketcher maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to help guard personally identifiable information. If transactions are offered on the RoomSketcher Services, transaction information is transmitted to and from RoomSketcher in encrypted form using industry-standard connections to help protect such information from interception. RoomSketcher restricts authorized access to your personal information to those persons who have a legitimate purpose to know that information to provide products or services to you and those persons you have authorized to have access to such information. Please be aware, however, that any email or other transmission you send through the internet cannot be completely protected against unauthorized interception.

### CHOICE/OPT-OUT

In order to provide service to you, we will send you communications related to your transactions, security or the administration of its website. From time to time, RoomSketcher and its affiliates may also wish to send you other messages or updates about the RoomSketcher Services, its affiliates, or their promotions and other activities. If you do not wish to receive non-transaction/security related communications from RoomSketcher and its affiliates, please contact customer service at +47 40 00 04 84.

### DATA QUALITY/ACCESS

We allow you to change, update, or delete the information you may provide in your optional registration form. If you would like to change, update, or delete your personal information, please send an email containing your request to customer service.

To the top
